Guide to the Marty Mann papers 1945-1968 (bulk 1950-1968)
Brown University Library
Marty Mann papers
Mann (Marty) papers
1945-1968
(bulk 1950-1968)
Ms.2010.010
John Hay Library University Archives and Manuscripts Box A Brown University Providence, RI, 02912 Telephone: Manuscripts: 401-863-3723; University Archives: 401-863-2148 Email: Manuscripts: hay@brown.edu; University Archives: archives@brown.edu
3 linear feet
Mann, Marty
Papers relating to her life.
Biographical/Historical Note
Biography of Marty Mann.
This is the second paragraph
Collection information
Scope note for Marty Mann.
This is the second paragraph.
There are no restrictions on access, except that the collection can only be seen by prior appointment. Some materials may be stored off-site and cannot be produced on the same day on which they are requested.
This collection is arragned in 3 series.
Series 1. Marty Mann
Subseries A. Awards
Subseries B. Biographical
Subseries C. Correspondence
Series 2. NCADD
Subseries A. Administration
Subseries B. Correspondence
Series 3. Photographs
Series 4. Objects
Administrative information
Gift of Marty Mann.
Additional information
See also the NCADD archives.
Publications by Marty Mann have been cataloged separately.
Names
Brown, Nicholas, 1854-1965; Cianci, Buddy; Coca Cola Company
Subjects
Fishing industry--Rhode Island; Rhode Island--History--20th century
Types of Materials
Broadsides; Photographs
Titles
Bible
- Marty Mann, Series 1
  - Awards, Series 1. Subseries A
    - Award to MM: The Elizabeth Blackwell Award - Outstanding Service to Mankind, 1963-06-09 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Annual Recognition Award Tribute to MM for the North American Association of Alcohol Programs with attached correspondence, 1968-09-16 - 1968-10-07 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Australia--Social life and customs
  - Biographical, Series 1. Subseries B
    - Notes by MM about herself (bio) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Curriculum Vitae (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Series 1. Subseries C
    - Correspondence from MM to Frances about 1965 "History of Alcoholism" speech preparation, 1965-07-27; Mann, Marty, 1934-1989; Smith, John, 1956-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Handwritten memo to Cora Louise Belford, Committee on Professional Relations, 26224; Mann, Marty, 1934-1989; Smith, John, 1956-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Belford, Cora Louise, 1967-; Lovecraft, Howard P.
- NCADD, Series 2
  - Administration, Series 2. Subseries A
    - Draft of "Statement of Purpose and Policy" for NCA, multiple drafts, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Ten Year Plan for NCA, verbatim report by MM, 1965-06-10 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Series 2. Subseries B
    - Memo to George Dimas from MM, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      History of the NCA from the perspective of Marty Mann
    - Letter to Brinkley Smithers from MM, 1962-12-30 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Photographs, Series 3
  - Various photographs of MM, 1944 - 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photographs inscribed to MM (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Objects, Series 4
  - Key to the City (Bel Air, MD) (undated) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Key to the City (Buffalo, NY) (Box 3, Folder 10)